<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>David Crowther</title>
    <link>http://www.davidcrowther.com</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 20:50:01 +0100</pubDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Guide to Short Copy vs Long Copy for Your Landing Page</title>
      <link>http://www.davidcrowther.com/blog/ultimate-guide-short-copy-vs-long-copy</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 20:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>David Crowther</author>
      <guid>http://www.davidcrowther.com/blog/ultimate-guide-short-copy-vs-long-copy</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://res.cloudinary.com/nerve/image/fetch/w_800,h_600,c_limit,f_auto/http://www.davidcrowther.com/assets/paper-planes.png&quot; alt=&quot;respond&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;Long copy vs. short copy: when and where to use them and why  &lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A battle has been raging in the field of marketing since its inception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On one side, stand the short hands. Their battle cries are, “People don’t want to read anymore,” and “Attention spans are at their lowest.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facing them are the purists who yell, “More Copy, More Sales!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So who will claim victory?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems this fight will, perhaps, forever end in a draw.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, experts tend to agree on one rule of thumb: &lt;strong&gt;Always write as much as you need to in order to get your customer to take action. Stop right there and write no more.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s pretty vague, I know. But, there are some factors to consider when deciding word count. These include the reputation of your company, the complexity of your product or service, its exclusivity, and its price tag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let’s start by seeing where using short copy tends to work and why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Where the Short Hand Prevails&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://res.cloudinary.com/nerve/image/fetch/w_800,h_600,c_limit,f_auto/http://www.davidcrowther.com/assets/people-apple-iphone-writing.jpg&quot; class=&quot;respond&quot; alt=&quot;Where the Short Hand Prevails&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proponents of short copy have a point when they say people don’t want to read anymore. According to the Nielson and Norman Group, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nngroup.com/articles/how-users-read-on-the-web/&quot;&gt;only 84 percent of web users read every word on a web page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ClickTale reports that just &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.clicktale.com/2007/10/05/clicktale-scrolling-research-report-v20-part-1-visibility-and-scroll-reach/&quot;&gt;22 percent of users even bother to scroll to the bottom of the webpage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Studies indicate short copy tends to work when your product meets the following criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’re company is well known and trusted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your product or offer is very simple and requires little explaining&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your price is inexpensive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your call-to-action costs no money: taking a free trial, signing up for a newsletter, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consider the following case studies, where short copy trumped long copy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fitness World, a well-known Scandinavian gym, &lt;a href=&quot;http://unbounce.com/conversion-rate-optimization/long-vs-short-conversion-marketing/&quot;&gt;increased conversions by 11 percent&lt;/a&gt; when it tested its long-form homepage against a shorter one. &lt;strong&gt;Its message was simple: join our gym and get fit.&lt;/strong&gt; The control page was loaded with specifics about the machines available, the classes offered and the people who worked there— all details users can see with a singe visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversion XL &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversionxl.com/4-cases-where-short-home-pages-outperformed-long-home-pages/&quot;&gt;created a long-form landing page for Motto Message&lt;/a&gt;, a company selling text-message marketing software.  It used much copy and graphics to answer questions discovered through customer-service research. However, Motto Message’s goal in having this landing page was to get users to take a free tour of the product and reach the pricing page. Testing the long-form page against a shorter page led 97 percent more people to take the tour and 21 percent more people to reach the pricing page. &lt;strong&gt;In this case, the initial demand from prospects was low, so users did not need much information to take an action.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design Boost, an online design school, wanted to use their home page to get people to sign up for a free course and to view course descriptions on other pages. They &lt;a href=&quot;http://unbounce.com/conversion-rate-optimization/long-vs-short-conversion-marketing/&quot;&gt;increased sign ups by 13 percent and click through by 25 percent&lt;/a&gt; when they tested a long-form control page against a shorter one. &lt;strong&gt;The rationale here is that the desired action sought from a customer was low:&lt;/strong&gt; We give you a free course for your email. &lt;strong&gt;We’re not talking dollars yet.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, much evidence suggests long copy is the way to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;When to go for the Long Haul&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://res.cloudinary.com/nerve/image/fetch/w_800,h_600,c_limit,f_auto/http://www.davidcrowther.com/assets/industry-rails-train-path.jpg&quot; class=&quot;respond&quot; alt=&quot;When to go for the Long Haul&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many studies suggest long copy works best when your product is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made by a well-known company &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expensive &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complex with many features &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Part of a specialized sector &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not unique &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unsought &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the following case studies &lt;strong&gt;where long copy stomped short copy in conversions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MecLabs ran a series of tests with a research partner selling a health product. In all three tests, &lt;strong&gt;the longer landing page trumped the shorter version, one with a 4-1 ratio.&lt;/strong&gt; The copy on the longer version was &lt;strong&gt;rife with details addressing doubts a customer may have about the product.&lt;/strong&gt; It shouldn’t be surprising that customers would want to know all they can about a product before putting it in their bodies.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers had this to say about their findings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In general, &lt;strong&gt;long copy offers the following advantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your visitors will have most of their questions answered and will have less anxiety&lt;/strong&gt; about ordering from you. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long copy can reduce customer service by qualifying your customers to a greater degree. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long copy with bolded or emphasized points can allow some of your visitors to skim&lt;/strong&gt;, while others more interested in specifics can find all the information they want. In this sense, long copy gives visitors more options. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long (and interesting) keyword-rich copy often &lt;strong&gt;performs well in natural search engines&lt;/strong&gt;.” &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crazy Egg, a web-analytics company offering heat-tracking software, &lt;a href=&quot;http://unbounce.com/conversion-rate-optimization/long-vs-short-conversion-marketing/&quot;&gt;increased conversions by 363 percent&lt;/a&gt; when Conversion Rate Experts made its home page about 20 times larger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did they do with that extra space?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They &lt;strong&gt;clearly explained&lt;/strong&gt; what heat maps were, how they worked, and how they could be of value to customers. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Justified price&lt;/strong&gt; with studies on the benefits of using eye-tracking software, as well as how Crazy Egg can deliver valuable data in a fraction of the cost and time it would take its competitors. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gave examples of how Crazy Egg features and services &lt;strong&gt;distinguish the company from its competitors.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out Conversion Rate Experts’ &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.conversion-rate-experts.com/crazy-egg-case-study/&quot;&gt;full report&lt;/a&gt; on their work with Crazy Egg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversion Rate Experts also &lt;a href=&quot;http://unbounce.com/conversion-rate-optimization/long-vs-short-conversion-marketing/&quot;&gt;helped Moz.com make $1 Million&lt;/a&gt; when they made the site’s home page larger by including more content such as testimonials, calls-to-action, tidbits from presentations and more. &lt;strong&gt;Moz is also a web-analytics company and it hired CRE to help sell its premium $599 a month package.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contentverve helped a little-known company &lt;a href=&quot;http://contentverve.com/how-long-should-a-landing-page-be-simple-tips/&quot;&gt;increase sign ups for a home energy audit by 63 percent&lt;/a&gt; when it made a longer landing page with more copy. &lt;strong&gt;This offer could involve a large investment. Thus, the company needs to address all the potential anxieties customers may have&lt;/strong&gt; about making a purchase, while still convincing them the offer is valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it’s important to remember that long copy won’t work for every product that’s complex or expensive. &lt;strong&gt;Research and testing will determine whether long or short copy is most effective in gaining conversions&lt;/strong&gt; for your product.  One thing is certain, however—your copy can’t suck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Long or Short: Quality Trumps All&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://res.cloudinary.com/nerve/image/fetch/w_800,h_600,c_limit,f_auto/http://www.davidcrowther.com/assets/black-and-white-sport-fight-boxer.jpg&quot; class=&quot;respond&quot; alt=&quot;Quality Trumps All&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comedian Jerry Seinfeld doesn’t care much for perceived attention spans. He once said, “People have an infinite attention span if you are entertaining them.”  What you need to get out of this is that, &lt;strong&gt;people are not going to read what fails to capture their attention.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how do you capture your target audience’s attention?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You mix it up and keep your copy fresh. You also filter out the words people don’t want to hear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://conversionxl.com/how-to-grab-and-hold-attention/&quot;&gt;Neuroscientists&lt;/a&gt; say our &lt;strong&gt;attentions are triggered by novelty, emotion and contrast&lt;/strong&gt;, or things that stand out. At the same time, we tend to ignore things that become repetitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider these tips on using copy to hook potential customers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start sentences with action verbs. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For long copy, write in 3-4 lines with subhead lines after every three paragraphs. The white space spreading this copy out creates contrast, while keeping it in one block of text can cause the reader to lose interest. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use emotionally-charged language to identify your customers’ problems and explain how your product can provide a solution. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlight key words or phrases&lt;/strong&gt; by italicizing, boldfacing, or font changing. This also helps the skimmers, which make up &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nngroup.com/articles/how-users-read-on-the-web/&quot;&gt;79 percent&lt;/a&gt; of readers on the Web. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilize bullet points as this will help readers digest information easily. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid jargon and speak in your customers’ language (More on this later). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your ability &lt;strong&gt;to capture the reader’s attention is perhaps most crucial when writing and designing the Value Proposition&lt;/strong&gt;, what Conversion XL calls &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversionxl.com/value-proposition-examples-how-to-create/&quot;&gt;“The #1 thing that determines whether people will keep reading or hit the back button.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What Is A Value Proposition?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://res.cloudinary.com/nerve/image/fetch/w_800,h_600,c_limit,f_auto/http://www.davidcrowther.com/assets/handwritten-italian-marketing-menu.jpg&quot; class=&quot;respond&quot; alt=&quot;What Is A Value Proposition&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A value proposition is a statement that &lt;strong&gt;promises value&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;distinguishes your product or service from the competition.&lt;/strong&gt; In an engaging and clear manner, it shows potential customers how your product will solve their problems or improve their situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It generally consists of a headline, which hooks the reader and presents the product’s end benefit; a sub headline, which in 2 to 3 sentences explains what the product is, for whom it’s for and how it’s used; a list of bullets which outline the product’s key benefits; and a visual that your target market can relate to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It helps the target audience answer the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is this company selling? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For whom is it for? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can I benefit from using this product? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why should I buy this product from this company? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out Conversion XL’s  &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversionxl.com/website-reviews-value-proposition-critique/&quot;&gt;analysis&lt;/a&gt; of good and bad value propositions, and look at this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marketingexperiments.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/MarketingExperiments-Value-Prop-Worksheet.pdf&quot;&gt;Value Proposition Worksheet&lt;/a&gt; designed by MarketingExperiments.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Show Them Exactly What You’re Offering&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://res.cloudinary.com/nerve/image/fetch/w_800,h_600,c_limit,f_auto/http://www.davidcrowther.com/assets/man-person-clouds-apple.jpg&quot; class=&quot;respond&quot; alt=&quot;Show Them Exactly What You’re Offering&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the length of your value proposition, &lt;strong&gt;a clear one can go a long way in conversions.&lt;/strong&gt; So, &lt;strong&gt;never be vague&lt;/strong&gt; in your value proposition, or any part of your copy for that matter. &lt;strong&gt;A customer should know exactly what he or she is being offered.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look at these case studies where clarity helped customers see value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An auto repair company increased conversions on a web page by 58 percent when it added detail to its vague headline. The control read, &lt;em&gt;“Simple Fix for Blown Head Gaskets.”&lt;/em&gt; The alternate version read, &lt;em&gt;“Repairs Blown Head Gaskets in Just One Hour.”&lt;/em&gt; The new version clearly explained the offer and even delivered a time frame for the service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content Verve tweaked a bullet point on a landing page promoting its e-book, &lt;em&gt;“7 Universal Conversion Optimization Principles.”&lt;/em&gt; The move &lt;a href=&quot;http://contentverve.com/case-study-increase-in-downloads-tweaking-bullet-point/&quot;&gt;increased downloads by 18.59 percent.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The control read, &lt;em&gt;“Insights and experience from 4 years of research and over 350 A/B tests distilled into one 26-page free ebook.”&lt;/em&gt; The new bullet point stated, &lt;em&gt;“Read the book in just 25 minutes and get insights from 4 years of research and over 350 A/B tests.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that before testing, author Michael Aagaard looked to a personal issue. He said he had many e-books on his iPad, but no time to read them all. He assumed other people must face this problem as well. So, &lt;strong&gt;he decided to test his hypothesis.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saxo Bank, of Denmark, increased sign-ups for a free trial of its Forex trading account, when it tested a revised version of its value proposition. &lt;a href=&quot;http://contentverve.com/online-copywriting-for-higher-conversions-what-i-learned-from-300-ab-tests-4-years-of-research/&quot;&gt;Check it out here&lt;/a&gt;. Notice the treatment is a lot clearer and it contains a headline that immediately mentions the offer’s end-benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CitiCliq &lt;a href=&quot;https://vwo.com/blog/using-ab-split-testing-to-refine-your-startups-positioning-90-increase-in-conversion-rate/&quot;&gt; tested a number of different phrases&lt;/a&gt; to use as a header on their landing page. CitiCliq creates websites for businesses. The headline that gained the most conversions read, &lt;em&gt;“Create a Web Page for Your Business.”&lt;/em&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using your copy to establish a connection with the reader can be essential to conversion.&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes, changing one word of copy can have this effect on your readers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read these case studies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matchoffice.com saw &lt;a href=&quot;http://contentverve.com/10-call-to-action-case-studies-examples-from-button-tests/&quot;&gt;a 14.79 percent increase in conversions&lt;/a&gt; by running a test that switched the phrase, “Order Information and Prices” with “Get Information and Prices.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://contentverve.com/10-call-to-action-case-studies-examples-from-button-tests/&quot;&gt;Counter verve and Unbounce ran a test on a PPC’s landing page&lt;/a&gt; by switching the word “your” to “my” in the phrase, “Start Your Free 30-Day Trial.” The result was a 90 percent increase in conversions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice that the word “order” from the first example expressed a demand, while “Get” expressed the idea that the customer was going to be provided with something. &lt;strong&gt;Customers really want to hear about what you can do for them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the second example, “my” made the &lt;strong&gt;user experience sound more personal&lt;/strong&gt; as opposed to “your” which indicated a detached second-person connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Keep it Simple&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://res.cloudinary.com/nerve/image/fetch/w_800,h_600,c_limit,f_auto/http://www.davidcrowther.com/assets/camera-technology-display-items.jpg&quot; class=&quot;respond&quot; alt=&quot;Keep it Simple&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the major walls standing in the way of expressing clarity and creating connections with a customer through copy is “Marketeze” or “Market Jargon.” Call it whatever you want, just keep it out of your copy, especially the value proposition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to speak in your customers’ language and to do that you need to know your target market as best you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here’s some home work. P.S. some of it requires field work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send your customers surveys asking them to rate certain pieces of copy. Michael Masterson &amp;amp; Mike Palmer’s Copy Logic! Service does this through surveys that utilize a number system and no room for comments, so your feelings won’t get hurt. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send customers emails asking them to rate your copy or request a testimonial about a product. &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/5-landing-page-tweaks-to-boost-conversion-rates/&quot;&gt;Check out my blog post on landing pages for more insight on testimonials.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitor your social media presence. Read Daniel Bursetin’s MarketingExperiments.com &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marketingexperiments.com/blog/research-topics/social-media-research-topics/social-media-value-prop.html&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; for some good advice on utilizing social media to learn about your ideal customers. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interview customers in person at shops. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interview your competitors’ customers too. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The survey and interview process can be very helpful when you’re asking the right questions. Conversion XL created &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversionxl.com/quick-course-on-effective-website-copywriting/&quot;&gt;the following list&lt;/a&gt; of questions you may want to ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who are you? What do you do? (customer profile) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does our product help you do? (helps you understand how they use it, tells you words they use to describe our product) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which parameters did you compare on different options? (which features matter) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What were the most important ones? (key pains to solve) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which alternatives did you consider? (competitors we have to look at) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What made you choose our product? (our key advantage) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What were the biggest hesitations and doubts before the purchase? (things we have to address in the copy) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Were there questions you needed answers to, but couldn’t find any? (necessary information to provide) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What information would have helped you make the decision faster? (same as above) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In which words would you recommend it to somebody you know? (words they use to describe our product) &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pay close attention to the information you gather. &lt;strong&gt;The words used in those responses should be reflected on to your copy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that Moz.com, which made $1 Million with its super-long web page, took customer feedback into great account while developing the dollar-making page. Through customer-service research, Conversion Rate Experts &lt;strong&gt;gathered questions customers had about the product and used their own language when addressing those concerns.&lt;/strong&gt; They even interviewed former customers who had canceled subscriptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there is also another group of people you should &lt;strong&gt;pay just as much attention to—your competitors.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Know Your Enemy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://res.cloudinary.com/nerve/image/fetch/w_800,h_600,c_limit,f_auto/http://www.davidcrowther.com/assets/nature-walking-animal-strong.jpg&quot; class=&quot;respond&quot; alt=&quot;Know Your Enemy&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversionxl.com/how-to-come-up-with-a-value-proposition-when-what-you-sell-isnt-unique/&quot;&gt;Conversion XL explains&lt;/a&gt;, monitoring your competitors is not about copying what you think works best for them. &lt;strong&gt;It’s about seeing where they fall short and you excel.&lt;/strong&gt; While many factors of a web page can be tweaked to highlight this key feature, copy can help you directly express its value to customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;This Is the End&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long Copy nor Short Copy will get you the conversions you’re looking for unless your copy is clear and powerful. Always look to express your product as something of value that not only stands out from the competition but meets the needs of the market it targets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are some things to consider when coming up with a word gauge. Long copy usually works well with complex produces with many features and in niche markets. They tend to have a heftier price tag. Meanwhile, inexpensive offers that are simple to understand tend to require less copy. It should be very easy for customers to complete the transaction without any fluff getting in the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, only research and testing will determine how many words you need to get your customers to buy your product. Know your customers, know your competitors, know your product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t ever stop testing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The copy on your web page, like the web page as a whole, needs to be an ever evolving creature.  It needs to adapt to new challenges and changes: shifts in customer mindset, what they expect from a company, what devices they are on etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It needs to optimize constantly or perish like the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Landing Page Tweaks That Will Really Boost Your Conversion Rates</title>
      <link>http://www.davidcrowther.com/blog/5-landing-page-tweaks-to-boost-conversion-rates</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 07:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>David Crowther</author>
      <guid>http://www.davidcrowther.com/blog/5-landing-page-tweaks-to-boost-conversion-rates</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/lp-machine.png&quot; class=&quot;respond&quot; alt=&quot;Conversion Rate Optimization&quot; width=&quot;640px&quot; height=&quot;543px&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;So, you’ve created an awesome advertising campaign for your business or product. Your ads are turning heads, your website is popping up on search results, and your social media presence is influencing clicks.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have major traffic coming on to your landing page.
But, there seems to be a jam. Your visitors are facing some road blocks keeping them from becoming leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel like you need to destroy your landing page and start from scratch? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don’t fret.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider just making a few renovations on your landing page to convince your Web visitors that it’s a place they want to stay on and explore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just running some tests by making minor changes to landing-page variables such as imagery, color scheme, and even words can generate major conversions.
And just a little bit of conversion can go a long way. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.wishpond.com/post/67068435596/landing-pages-the-fundamentals-and-conversion&quot;&gt;Wishpond’s&lt;/a&gt; example. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Let’s say you’re an online retailer with 15,000 monthly site-visits. Your customers are spending, on average, $35 each time they buy. If your online site saw a conversion rate increase of 1% over that month, you’d see a $5,250 increase in revenue.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty interesting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, why stop there? You want to keep testing until you’ve reached your conversion goals. Then, come up with higher goals. And test some more. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let’s start testing. Here are some points to consider when building or tweaking landing pages. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/first-impressions.jpg&quot; class=&quot;respond&quot; alt=&quot;Make a Great First Impression&quot; width=&quot;640px&quot; height=&quot;209px&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;1. Make a Great First Impression&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Studies show that Web users are picky bunch. They devote very little time to deciding whether to stick around on your landing page – around three to eight seconds. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this time, they subconsciously answer questions such as&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is this site relevant to the link I clicked?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it visually appealing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it worth my time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming your link sent them to your right landing page, let’s get started with visuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that will capture your Web traffic’s attention will be the main image. So, it’s pretty important to have one. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve heard the expression, “A picture is worth a thousand words.” Well, it’s probably worth much more than that because an image &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.wishpond.com/post/67068435596/landing-pages-the-fundamentals-and-conversion&quot;&gt;can express ideas better than any text&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Picture this&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2003, Harvard economist Sendhil Mullainathan conducted a study while working with a South African bank that sent people letters offering short-term loans. He varied certain factors among the letters such as interest rates and whether to include an image on the corner of the letter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study revealed that including an image of a smiling woman “had as much impact on the response rate as dropping the interest rate by four percentage points.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As great as that move was, however, a picture of a smiling woman won’t win over every visitor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Frame Your Landing Page for Your Unique Visitors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll have to showcase an image that resonates with your target market: Something that makes them see your business as friendly, trustworthy and reliable. You can figure this out by testing different images on your landing page and seeing which ones produce the largest conversion rates. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the magic of A/B testing. Something as easy as using one image instead of another can create more customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most cases, however, show that photos of real people rather than stock or model photos increase conversions, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.kissmetrics.com/personality-and-trust/&quot;&gt;often by 50 percent&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may be because “images of people communicate trust better than any other image can.” We also respond more emotionally to images of people as apposed to text or random images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;People Power Put to the Test&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Media Art, an e-commerce company, increased conversions by about 95 percent when images of paintings on its control landing page were swapped for images of the artists who made them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brookdale Living, which offers community-living options for senior citizens, increased conversions by 3.92 percent and gained $106,000 in additional revenue after conducting a simple test. Brookdale pitted a control page with no image against one with an image of a smiling resident and one with a video featuring residents. The one with the single image produced the most conversions.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harrington Movers ran a test using a generic stock photo, a photo of the smiling moving crew and a photo of the company truck. The crew came out on top with a conversion rate of 45.5 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Keep It Pretty … Sometimes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much research suggests that images of &lt;a href=&quot;http://unbounce.com/conversion-rate-optimization/images-and-conversion-rates/&quot;&gt;attractive people convert more than images of non-attractive people&lt;/a&gt;. Studies even indicate that attractive people are judged to be more intelligent, charismatic and successful than everyone else.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, as I will emphasize throughout this article, there is no sure-fire formula in the world of Conversion Rate Optimization. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;When Pretty Didn’t Cut It&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T-Mobile once featured images of model-spokesperson Catherine Zeta Jones throughout their website. In 2009, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uie.com/articles/deciding_when_graphics_help/&quot;&gt;UIE studied the company’s Web traffic&lt;/a&gt; and found that many users became irritated after seeing several photos of Jones, but not enough photos that were descriptive of T-mobile’s products. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One older shopper was specifically searching for a phone with large buttons. “She [Jones] is a very pretty woman,” the shopper said. “I just wish I could see her buttons.”   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it’s important to note that when these companies successfully used images of people, those pictures were relevant to their target markets. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to find the best image for your landing page, you must know your visitors as best you can. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, do some research. Figure out which pictures will frame your business as friendly, trustworthy and awesome to your Web visitors. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/colored-pencils.png&quot; class=&quot;respond&quot; alt=&quot;Use The Right Colors&quot; width=&quot;640px&quot; height=&quot;181px&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;2. Use The Right Colors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great way to gain your viewers’ attentions and make them feel comfortable on your landing page is by using the right color scheme. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When used correctly, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.kissmetrics.com/psychology-of-color-and-conversions/&quot;&gt;color can elicit desired emotions and even reactions&lt;/a&gt;. Thus, mastering the use of color is essential, not just for designers, but for marketers as well.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Consider this&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.emeraldinsight.com/doi/full/10.1108/00251740610673332&quot;&gt;peer-reviewed article&lt;/a&gt; published on the scholarly journal “Management Decision,” mangers can “use color to increase or decrease appetite, enhance mood, calm down customers, and reduce perception of waiting time among others.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same article concluded that it takes a customer about 90 seconds to form an opinion about a product. 62-90 percent of that interaction is determined by color.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, why is color so influential? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The field dedicated to answering this question is called &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.crazyegg.com/2011/10/03/persuasive-power-color/&quot;&gt;color psychology&lt;/a&gt; and knowing a bit about it can lead to golden conversion rates. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the gist: Seeing color affects a region of our brain called the hypothalamus, causing it to shoot signals that eventually reach our thyroid glands. These glands affect mood, emotions and behavior. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, before you begin playing with the color pallet, it’s important to ask yourself some questions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What emotions and perceptions do I want my target market to associate with my business? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try making a list of answers. Then, explore how you can accomplish your goals with the colors at your disposal. 
Here is something to get you thinking about color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Colors and their Meanings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Based on reports by &lt;a href=&quot;http://unbounce.com/landing-pages/color-theory-and-conversion/&quot;&gt;Unbounce&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.kissmetrics.com/psychology-of-color-and-conversions/&quot;&gt;Kissmetrics&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blue is a calm color that’s linked to trust, loyalty and sincerity.&lt;br&gt;
Side Note: Some studies suggest blue should not be used with anything to do with food as the color is linked to appetite suppression. In fact, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.3fatchicks.com/how-the-color-blue-supresses-your-appetite/&quot;&gt;dieticians have used blue plates to prevent people from overeating&lt;/a&gt;. The reasoning could lie in our evolutionary make up. With the exception of blueberries and blue corn, there are not many naturally occurring blue foods out there. So, our brain could associate blue with something not safe for consumption. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Green is the easiest color for our eyes to process. It’s associated with health, restoration, environmentalism and &lt;a href=&quot;http://psp.sagepub.com/content/early/2012/03/15/0146167212436611.abstract&quot;&gt;creativity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Red is known to quicken the heart rate, seemingly making time go faster than it actually is. It represents urgency and is linked to strength, energy and excitement. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pink is generally seen as a romantic color that’s associated with warmth, love and sexuality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Purple is linked to luxury, quality and truth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Black is associated with sophistication, luxury and sleekness. Consider the color scheme on the Web pages for high-rolling companies like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lamborghini.com/en/home/&quot;&gt;Lamborghini&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://us.louisvuitton.com/eng-us/homepage?campaign=sem_BRAN-BREX&quot;&gt;Louis Vuitton&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
Side Note: Black is also associated with death and mourning. These subjects may or may not fit well with your target market. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Orange represents competition and excitement. Many sports teams such as the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.denverbroncos.com/&quot;&gt;Denver Broncos&lt;/a&gt; use it heavily on their website and gear. Orange is also linked to affordability. Think about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.biglots.com/&quot;&gt;Big Lots&lt;/a&gt; logo. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yellow is an attention-grabbing color. Think about wet-floor signs. It’s also associated with happiness and fun, according to a report by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/branding-and-the-psychology-of-color-2012-12?op=1&quot;&gt;Business Insider&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also explore various color combinations by using a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worqx.com/color/color_wheel.htm&quot;&gt;color wheel&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just remember: It’s not what you think looks nice. It’s what your customers know looks nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Colors and Contrast&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An important factor to consider when testing color schemes is contrast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrast promotes a user-friendly Web experience, and it enhances readability. For example, letters are most easily read when they are placed on a background with plenty of contrast. Think black letters on a white piece of paper. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And trust me, the text on your page matters.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/book-bird.jpg&quot; class=&quot;respond&quot; alt=&quot;Make Your Copy Count&quot; width=&quot;640px&quot; height=&quot;281px&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3. Make Your Copy Count&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to use copy to your advantage is by clearly, and quickly communicating to your visitors that you’re offering something valuable that meets their specific needs and wants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copy can be strategically used at certain points of your landing page such as the USP and CTA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;USP (Unique Selling Point): This is what makes your business and product stand out from the competition. It can be illustrated on a header and backed up by a short list of benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CTA (Call-to-Action) button: This is the button that users click on in order to become leads by filling out forms with their information. Users fill out these forms for various reason. They include the following &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starting free trials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subscribing to newsletters &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making appointments &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Placing orders &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Etc. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Tips for Good Copy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make it Clear. Your visitors should know exactly what they are being offered.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Example of Clear Cut Copy:&lt;/strong&gt; CitiCliq, a company that designs web pages for businesses, &lt;a href=&quot;https://vwo.com/blog/using-ab-split-testing-to-refine-your-startups-positioning-90-increase-in-conversion-rate/&quot;&gt;tested a number of different phrases&lt;/a&gt; to use as a header on their landing page. The clearest one produced the most conversions. It read, “Create a Web Page for Your Business.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make it short. Your visitors are not going to read every word. They’re looking for the words that hook them and convince them you have what they are looking for. No more than five words is usually ideal. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Start sentences and phrases with verbs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speak in a language that is consistent with that of your target market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don’t tell people what to do. Tell them what you can do for them. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What do you think of these phrases? Which do you prefer?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Get Access to Leads” Vs. “Order now”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Get the Time Slot You Want.” Vs. “Book an Appointment”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice that verbs like “Order” and “Book” suggest a demand, while words such as “Get” imply that you’ll be receiving something. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Even replacing a word can work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matchoffice.com saw &lt;a href=&quot;http://contentverve.com/10-call-to-action-case-studies-examples-from-button-tests/&quot;&gt;a 14.79 percent increase in conversions&lt;/a&gt; by running a test that switched the phrase, “Order Information and Prices” with “Get Information and Prices.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://contentverve.com/10-call-to-action-case-studies-examples-from-button-tests/&quot;&gt;Counter verve and Unbounce ran a test on a PPC’s landing page&lt;/a&gt; by switching the word “your” to “my” in the phrase, “Start Your Free 30-Day Trial.” The result was a 90 percent increase in conversions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind; however, these are only suggestions to get you brainstorming about the kinds of tests you may want to run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember I said, keep it short? Well, some companies saw results by going against that rule. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Long form&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WriteWork.com, a subscription-based educational website for college students, ran a test by switching their control CTA button labeled “Create My Account” with “Create My Account and Get Started.” The company earned a &lt;a href=&quot;http://contentverve.com/10-call-to-action-case-studies-examples-from-button-tests/&quot;&gt;31.03 percent increase in conversions&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note, however, that WriteWork.com’s target market analysis indicated most people who sign up did so when they were eager to get their writing process started immediately.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Making Your CTA Buttons Stand Out&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;CTA buttons need to capture attention, so color-coating them with a hue that contrasts with the color scheme of the Web page, while still fitting with the overall design, may help.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Green Vs. Red&lt;/strong&gt;: Performable, a marketing automation company, increased conversions by 21 percent just by &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.hubspot.com/blog/tabid/6307/bid/20566/The-Button-Color-A-B-Test-Red-Beats-Green.aspx&quot;&gt;changing the color&lt;/a&gt; of the CTA button from green to red. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Try surrounding your CTA in white space. This would devoid the button of anything interesting around it causing it to stand out. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make the button large enough to be seen, but not so large that it drives attention from other key elements on your page such as the main image and the USP. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/testimonials-icon.png&quot; class=&quot;respond&quot; alt=&quot;Testimonials&quot; width=&quot;400px&quot; height=&quot;293px&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;4. Let Them Know What Your Happy Customers are Saying&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testimonials and customer reviews are becoming increasingly important factors in CRO. Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People want to know what others think about your product or service before they invest in you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testimonials can also add personality and trustworthiness to your business, when they come from real and reliable individuals. With that said, make a real testimonial seem as real as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Tips on Keeping it Real&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include the author’s name and, if applicable, title.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include a picture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t accept over-the-top testimonials as these may seem “too good to be true” and raise speculation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure they specifically explain how your business or product helped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before choosing whose testimonial to feature on your landing page, ask yourself this question. Whom does my target market really trust the most? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An expert in your field?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The CEO of your company?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A typical customer?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or someone else?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer to that question, like so many others, depends on your visitors’ presumptions and perceptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Look at Whom This Person Chose&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital marketing expert Neil Patel received higher conversions for his website Quick Sprout by showcasing testimonials from big businesses rather than small ones. Patel used a &lt;a href=&quot;http://unbounce.com/landing-pages/why-people-dont-trust-your-landing-page-testimonials/&quot;&gt;testimonial by Techcrunch founder Michael Arrington.&lt;/a&gt; The quote next to his picture read “Neil increased TechCrunch’s traffic by 30 percent within 2 months.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An important point to take away from that testimonial is that it came from an authoritative figure from a successful company that was relevant to Neil’s field. The testimonial was also very clear. It specifically explained how Neil helped solve a problem TechCrunch was facing and it even gave statistics to back it up. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, your customers may have different presumptions about different people involved with your business. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.kissmetrics.com/personality-and-trust/&quot;&gt;Edelman’s&lt;/a&gt; chart based on its Trust Barometer Executive Summary for some insight into how the trustworthiness of different spokespersons has changed among customers over time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, keep in mind that this data is just something to get you thinking. You have to study your own Web traffic, run tests and discover whom they tend to trust the most.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/navigate.jpg&quot; class=&quot;respond&quot; alt=&quot;Navigate&quot; width=&quot;640px&quot; height=&quot;426px&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;5. Help Your Visitors Navigate Your Landing Page&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve covered some important landing-page variables that can catch your visitors’ attentions, gain their trust and convince them your offers are valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, you still need to smoothly guide your Web traffic through all that neat information so they won’t wander around aimlessly and bounce. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Directional cues such as arrows can help you achieve this goal. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about directional cues as your landing page’s tour guides. They navigate your Web audience through your page’s main attractions in an orderly fashion. If they did a good job, your visitors would not only want to come back, they’ll want to empty their wallets at your souvenir shop. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Here are a few directional cues to test on your landing page&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eye Direction: The first thing your Web traffic will notice on your landing page will be the picture of a person. Then, they will focus on the person’s eyes because we are subconsciously wired to go there when we see someone’s face.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Look at this&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
On its landing page, Kissmetrics utilized the principal of eye direction by strategically placing an image of a smiling man on a spot where he is &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.wishpond.com/post/93218092881/how-to-use-directional-cues-to-optimize-landing-page&quot;&gt;directly looking at the page’s CTA button&lt;/a&gt;. The button is also right below the page’s USP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lines, arrows and pointed fingers: Humans subconsciously follow lines to their points of origin. Use this to your advantage and lead your Web traffic to conversion. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Utilize the power of white space to isolate and bring attention to different factors&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point of directional cues is to establish encapsulation on your landing page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Encapsulation establishes hierarchy based on color, format, contrast and the directional cues above. An eye on a page with little encapsulation tends to wander from-and-to different focus points with no clear sense of direction and leaves before seeing real value. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An eye on a page with encapsulation flows in a straight line from focus point to focus point, recognizing value throughout. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Big Point&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CRO is an endless game of testing. It can be an eye-opening and thought provoking experience. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key is to study your potential customers, learn what they want, and figure out how you can help them—Better than the competition can.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your landing page is where you put what you’ve learned to the test and where you turn curious visitors into enthusiastic leads. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider what we’ve covered:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The impact of imagery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The power of color&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The influence of the right words&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The trustworthiness of testimonials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The order of your landing page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, go research your target market and &lt;a href=&quot;/convert/&quot;&gt;kick off some tests&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
